Samuel Rakoton. Java EE Developer

Montreal(OC): 647-614-0229

samuel.rakoton@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-rakoton29 | www.samrak.info/welcome

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

Bilingual (English/French) software developer with proven experience in **CRM development using Java EE** to develop, test, debug, and deliver versions of the application into integration and production environments. Self-Motivated and team player. Enjoy learning new technologies to better implement requirements. Strong focus on product and customer expectations.

Key Proficiencies

• Programming:

Java7/8, UML, ERD, SQL, JSF2, html5, css3, JPA/Hibernate, SQL, concurrency, multi-threading

Environment/Framework/Library:

V-Cycle, Agile, React, Soap, REST, Eclipse, Spring MVC, SpringBoot, SpringSecurity, Maven2, JUnit, SqlDeveloper, MySql, Sonar, Jenkins, SVN, Git, Tomcat/GlassFish, Postman, VSCode, MySqlWorkbench

• Trouble shooting tools:

ClearQuest, Jira, Synergy, DOORS T-REK, Mantis, Rally, Microsoft Office

• Other:

- Customer focus: End product Quality | direct interface to customer requests
- Trouble shooting
- Task Prioritization
- Adaptable, Empathetic
- Constructive and collaborative approach
- Willingness to learn new skills

IT PROFESSIONNAL EXPERIENCE

Java EE Software Developer Aubay – Paris, FRANCE

Nov.2018 - Sept 2019

CRM to manage financing requests from French wineries to the ministry of agriculture.

- Requirements implemented, tested, bug fixed, versions of application delivered into integration and production environments.
- **Front**: JSF2+ SpringMVC **Back**: Soap WebService+Entities+JPAHibernate+ DAO+Oracle Database
- **Programming**: Java7, JSF2, SQL

Performance: 80 Problem Reports fixed and 3 new expressions of needs implemented within the last 6-month.

Environment: Eclipse, Maven2, SoapUI, SpringMVC, SQL Developer, Mantis, Tomcat, Glassfish, Sonar, Hudson, Jenkins, Agile

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Quality Assurance Consultant Randstad Group- Paris, FRANCE

Mar. 2015-Sept. 2017

Process & Product Quality Manager IDEMIA

Mar. 2016- Sept. 2017

Quality Assurance Management of a Telecom Business Unit (BU) and its Products

- ISO9001: B.U processes formalized. Yearly Management Reviews organized.
- Product Quality: Customers audits and claims supported: 8D coordinated- Complaint dashboard created, KPI monitored and reported to the BU director.
- Project Management: customer onboarding new scheme | Quality contract.

Performance: Managed to keep the BU director CPMS KPI under 0.08 CPMS

Environment: ISO9001, Business Processes, Project Management, 8D, CA/PA, FMEA, Risk Mgt.

Software Quality Assurance Representative GE Healthcare

Mar. 2015- Jan. 2016

Quality assurance for a medical application software development

- Product development process review before audit following the SDLC
- DoD and DoR completeness and harmonization check.

Environment: Medical Device, IEC62304, Rally, ClearQuest, Confluence, Agile

Samuel Rakoton Page 1/2

Software Suppliers Certification Auditor *Bombardier – Toronto, CANADA Global 5,6,7,8000 Global Vision Flight Deck - Avionics Certification Project*

Sept.2010- Jun. 2013

• Audit of suppliers avionic embedded software development | Compliance Reported to TCCA **Performance**: 4 avionics embedded software parts certified. ACE Company Award received on dedication to the Global 5000-6000 aircraft avionics certification.

Environment: ARP4754, DO178B, DO254, MISRA, MS-Project, TCCA, DAL A/C/D, V-Cycle

Hardware Qualification Technician Thales – Toronto, CANADA

Mar. 2010- Sept. 2010

Train electronic system validation

• Train system (VOBC): hardware electronic boards qualification by reviewing tests, test results, traceability, inspecting schematics and electronic boards, demonstrating and analyzing requirements.

Environment: Doors, Electronics Hardware, V-Cycle

Previous Experience details available on request

Software Development Assurance MTU Aero Engines – Munich, GERMANYJan. 2009- Dec. 2009Software Functional Verification Sagem Defense & Security – Paris, FRANCESept. 2007- Dec. 2008Electronic internship SAFRAN (Snecma Moteur) – Paris, FRANCEMar. 2005- Sept. 2005

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Credential Assessment from the University of Toronto Comparative Education Service - Available

MASTER Automation, Electrical Engineering & Industrial Computing U.T.B.M, France	2007
BACHELOR Aeronautical & Industrial Systems Engineering I.U.P Evry, France	2005
BACHELOR Instrumentation Technology in Physics I.U.T Créteil, France	2002

Trainings & Development

Java EE Training M21, France	Jun - Aug 2018
Project management, CMA Paris	Jan - Apr-2016
Financial Math, CMA Paris	Nov 2015- Mar 2016
French Fluent - English Fluent	

Samuel Rakoton Page 2/2